# JOOSEP KÕIVISTIK SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

(+45) 50302356 jokoivi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jokoivi

#### **Profile**



I'm an enthusiastic senior frontend engineer who's specialised in building complex SaaS web applications based on the Angular framework.

I love working in large teams where there is a lot of interaction, code reviews, retros, good standards and everyone contributing and learning from one-another. I prefer an environment where there is a lot of collaboration between tech and product in order to deliver the best possible solutions.

#### Technical

#### **BASE SKILLS**

		Years
HTML / SCSS		17
Javascript		15
Typescript	- 1	5
Angular		5
Redux / Ngrx		5
AngularJS		8
React		1
RESTful APIs		

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Building complex applications
Team work
Leading projects
Planning & Grooming
UI & UX design
Mentoring juniors
Responsive design

#### **TOOLS**

Jira / Confluence
Github / Gitlab
Photoshop
Windows
scrum
WSL (ubuntu)

## Experience

## Nordea Senior IT Developer

Largest bank in the Nordics

• Working at the "Digital Wealth" unit dealing with holdings and savings for private clients



2022 - Now

#### 2020 - 2022

## Kahoot! / Actimo Senior Frontend Engineer

In 2020, Actimo was acquired by kahoot with the goal of being able to put more resources into growing their corporate solutions.

 I still continued working on the 'Actimo' platform, so i have rather summarised all the highlights in the next section



Actimo
Senior Frontend Engineer

2017 - 2020

A platform which allows companies to create their own branded employee apps for onboarding, communication, training, employee-manager evaluations and social interaction.

- During my time at Actimo, the whole platform has grown immensely both in terms of the
  overall feature offerings but also the architecture, scalability and code quality. Having always
  been either the only, or one of the two senior frontenders, I have played an integral role in
  most of the projects over the past 5 years. The most notable examples being:
  - Rebuilding the whole end-user facing app from scratch using Angular and NgRx
  - Gradual re-build of the editor-facing app (angular JS + Angular hybrid where all new development was in Angular and the most relevant pages, components and architecture were fully converted one project at the time)
  - · Actimo Academy feature -
  - The Editor feature Complete rebuild & revamp of the way we handled our user generated content, combining 6+ different page sets and concepts into a single unified pattern. -
  - Pulse & One-on-one manager / employee evaluation features
  - Social wall feature kind of like Facebook groups.
  - Dashboards feature Global stats page
  - Employee profiles
- · Countless of smaller features and enhancements
- On-boarding and mentoring 2 junior developers
- Running frontend workgroups, documenting processes and making sure we follow them.
- Helping with recruiting scouting for candidates, doing interviews and reviewing tests.



actimo.com

Tame 2016 - 2017

#### **Lead Frontend Developer**

At the time, it was a very fresh startup working on an all-in-one platform for organising events

- Working alongside the lead designer to come up with optimal ui/ux solutions / patterns
- Building up the features using React and NodeJs
- · Creating a modular and reusable component base



tame.events

# Agillic Aps Frontend Developer

2013 - 2016

Omnichannel marketing automation platform

- Designing and developing the user-interface for their "Match" product line / MVC based AngularJS web application
- Rewriting of a complex B2B web app "Dialogue" which was originally built upon now deprecated Flex framework. The new app was to be a proper modular, responsive / multi device capable HTML5 / AngularJS based MVC app using simple REST/json endpoints
- · communicating requests for api's and their model formats with the backend team in ukraine
- Enhancing & improving the existing UI



agillic.com

2012 - 2013

# Hapti.co (io-interactive's subsidiary) Junior Frontend Developer

A game studio which worked on a project called "Gameglobe" - a next gen browser game/portal driven by user generated content.

- Frontend implementation for new features using jquery & html
- · backend implementation using python/django
- · Ensuring cross browser compatability
- · Modifying designs in photoshop to be responsive
- · Finding bugs and improving the existing UI
- · Improving and cleaning the existing codebase



tiny.one/gameglobe

## Svejstrup & Lyng ApS Lead Frontend Developer

2011 - 2012

A tiny architecture bureau

- · Architectural 3D visualization.
- Creating and maintaining websites for various projects, sub-companies and assosiates.
- Designing logos, business cards.

#### Estonian defense forces

2009 - 2010

mandatory service of 9 months

Webox I/S web developer

2008 - 2009

A web design company i created with a few friends on the side of our studies

Creating simple home pages.

Education

# Odder Højskole

2011 - 2011

6 months course focusing on:

- Drawing
- Painting
- creativity and form
- Photography

# **Business Academy Arhus**

2007 - 2009

AP degree in multimedia design and communication

- Communication and presentation
- Design and visualization
- Interaction development
- Digital marketing

# Otepää Gymnasium

1994 - 2007

12 grade education

### Additional

#### **PERSONAL**

**LANGUAGES** 

**HOBBIES** 

Crafting / DIY

Location: Cph, Denmark

Nationality: Estonian

English | Fluent

| native

Photography / Videography

Born: Nov 23, 1987

Danish |Limited (module 4)

Estonian

Art projects

Web: koivistik.com